<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Newer Systems</title>
    <link>http://newer.systems/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Newer Systems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://newer.systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Settle the Score</title>
      <link>http://newer.systems/settle-the-score/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://newer.systems/settle-the-score/</guid>
      <description>english horn, trumpet, electric guitar, violin, computer - 4 minutes completed Winter 2022
program notes Settle the Score is a piece for five instruments: cor anglais, trumpet, electric guitar, violin, and computer. It can either be performed as a chamber work with all five parts, or any one part alone. The piece is designed so that each part has unique content and contour; each solo has different alternations of smooth and jagged music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commonplace Common Tones</title>
      <link>http://newer.systems/commonplacecommontones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://newer.systems/commonplacecommontones/</guid>
      <description>sinfonietta - 6 minutes completed Fall 2021
program notes Commonplace Common Tones explores relationships between overlapping groups, or groups which share elements. These relationships are present as subdivisions of the ensemble, collections of pitches, and rhythmic patterns. The piece contains 3 ‘kinds’ of music. The first is scattered in nature—utilizing varieties of sparse instrumental combinations, the second is chordal, and the third is driving and rhythmic. These are arranged across 6 sections each using a different combination of 2 overlapping pitch collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twenty-One Inventions</title>
      <link>http://newer.systems/21inventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://newer.systems/21inventions/</guid>
      <description>piano - 22 minutes in progress
program notes Twenty-One Inventions is a modular, multi-movement work for piano. The inventions are organized into seven, three-movement groups called sequences. These sequences can be played in any combination. I constructed each of the short inventions from one to seven contrapuntal strands. Inventions which share the same number of these strands are composed out in a similar fashion, and thus share a title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enter Ghost</title>
      <link>http://newer.systems/enterghost/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://newer.systems/enterghost/</guid>
      <description>voice, trumpet, bass clarinet, trombone - 6 minutes completed summer 2021
text -Enter Ghost- (trombone)
Marcellus: &amp;ldquo;Peace, break thee off; look, where it comes again!&amp;rdquo; (trumpet)
Bernardo: &amp;ldquo;In the same figure, like the king that&amp;rsquo;s dead.&amp;rdquo; (bass clarinet)
Marcellus: &amp;ldquo;Thou art a scholar; speak to it *Horatio.&amp;rdquo;
Bernardo: &amp;ldquo;Looks it not like the king? Mark it *Horatio.&amp;rdquo;
Horatio: &amp;ldquo;Most like: it harrows me with fear and wonder.&amp;rdquo; (voice)
Bernardo: &amp;ldquo;It would be spoke to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moment / Time -Practice</title>
      <link>http://newer.systems/momenttimepractice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://newer.systems/momenttimepractice/</guid>
      <description>open ensemble - variable completed Fall 2020
program notes The foundation for moment / time -Practice are the six phrases: for only a moment, for only a breath, for beyond a breath, for only your mind, for only your body, for beyond you.
Even when things seem still, they are changing. Imagine for a moment the temporality of plate tectonics or the forming and moving of glaciers. These temporalities are vast compared to our breath, the primary measurement of the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CO</title>
      <link>http://newer.systems/co/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://newer.systems/co/</guid>
      <description>alto saxophone, piano - 5 minutes completed Winter 2019
program notes CO is a duo for saxophone and piano premiered at the inaugural Dot-the-Line Festival in Jeonju, South Korea. The work grew out of a set of number lines marked with co-prime proportions. Out of each number line a miniature was constructed, which devided material in time. These self-contained mini structures contain a wide variety of materials.
score video Doug O&amp;rsquo;Connor, alto saxophone - Eunmi Ko, piano</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://newer.systems/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://newer.systems/about/</guid>
      <description>full bio Currently based in Rochester, New York, Tucker Johnson&amp;#39;s musical practice includes works for soloists, ensembles, and electronic media.
His music has been programmed and honored at festivals and events, including the inaugural Dot-The-Line new music festival (Seoul), Longy Divergent Studio (Boston), soundSCAPE Festival (Cesena), Composing in the Wilderness (Prince William Sound &amp;amp; NYC), Shastra Rhythm Workshop (New Jersey), and the National Young Composers&amp;rsquo; Challenge (Orlando). In 2021, he was awarded the Marjorie Jane Brewster Memorial Music Scholarship; a scholarship awarded each year to one graduating Penn State student to pay for graduate studies at another institution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>...for the discernment of vocations with...</title>
      <link>http://newer.systems/forthediscernment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://newer.systems/forthediscernment/</guid>
      <description>tabla, percussion quartet - 8 minutes completed Summer 2018
program notes Composed in 2018 for the SHASTRA Rhythm Workshop, ...for the discernment of vocations... deals with the iterative improvisation found in traditional tabla performance and iterative pitch transformations. The piece is in two sections: an introduction which is free rhythmically, and the rhtyhmic tabla improvisation. The tabla&amp;rsquo;s improvisation is broken up by contrapuntal episodes in the mallet percussion.
score video Shawn Mativetsky, tabla - New Jersey Percussion Ensemble - Payton MacDonald, Conductor</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>list of works</title>
      <link>http://newer.systems/list_of_works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://newer.systems/list_of_works/</guid>
      <description>large ensemble ├── Commonplace Common Tones [2021]
└── sinfonietta - 6 minutes
chamber ├── Enter Ghost [2021]
└── voice, trumpet, bass clarinet, trombone - 6 minutes
├── Moment / Time -Practice [2020]
└── open ensemble - variable
├── CO [2019]
└── alto saxophone, piano - 5 minutes
├── ...for the discernment of vocations with... [2018]
└── tabla, percussion quartet - 8 minutes
solo ├── Twenty-One Inventions [2022]
└── piano - 22 minutes</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
